巴黎 1931年
各位
What do you know, boys?
巴比 快过来 让你见个人
Hey, Papi, get over here. I got someone I want you to meet.
罗兰·罗格朗
Roland Legrand.
向警方泄密的时候被抓到
Caught this fuckin' goat singing like a canary to the police.
这就是你的下场
This is what happens when you cross me.
把他赶出去
Get this piece of shit outta here.
你有什么东西给我
So, what do you got for me?
易如反掌 如你所说
Piece of cake. Just like you said.
你私藏了没有
You pocket any for yourself?
有几个大的
Yeah, just a couple of big ones.
你还真是狗胆包天
You sure got some balls on you.
你要是敢骗我 包管叫你没有蛋
You try to hustle me, and I'll cut 'em the fuck off.
来一万
Good for 10,000.
晚上开心吗
Did you have a good night?
开心 - 那还成
Yep. - At least you did.
或许能让你乐一下
Maybe this'll cheer you up.
拿去吧
Take it.
给你的
It's for you.
这几颗大的留给我们
A couple of the big ones for us.
你疯了
You're crazy.
你要去哪里 - 卡斯提不希望我早走
Where you goin'? - Castili doesn't want me leaving early.
卡斯提去死吧
To hell with Castili.
我们玩玩吧
Let's go have some fun.
把你的皱眉倒过来吧
Turn that frown upside-down.
我就知道你想寻开心
I know you wanna have some fun.
我爱你
I love you.
再说一遍
Say that again.
慢点
Slower.
我
I...
爱
love...
你
you.
我想要一幢房子
I want a house.
在乡下 和你长大的地方一样
In the countryside, like where you grew up.
你描述的真好听 骑着你的小马
You make it sound so nice, riding your little horsey around.
今天就走吧
Let's go today.
我在乡下怎么挣钱呢
How am I gonna earn in the country?
那儿没有东西偷
There's nothing to steal.
找份工作吧
We'll get jobs.
我一晚上挣的比乡下人一年挣的都多
I made more last night than most people in the country make in a year.
再宽我六个月
Gimme six months.
我赚到的钱 会比卡斯提和那些二流子更多
I'll be making more money than Castili and all those bums.
我不想等上六个月
I don't want to wait six months.
我来收房租
I'm here for the rent.
我来了
All right. I'm comin', I'm comin'.
是他 - 搞什么鬼
It's him. - What the fuck?
你因杀害罗兰·罗格朗被逮捕了
You're under arrest for the murder of Roland Legrand.
扯淡
What are you talkin' about?
他昨晚被杀了 有证人指认你
Well, he was murdered last night. A witness identified you.
皮条客罗兰·罗格朗
The pimp, Roland Legrand.
你认识他 对吧
You know him, right?
你找错人了 伙计 我整晚都在泡她 - 来 我们走
You got the wrong guy, pal. I was with her all night. - Come on. Let's go.
好 让我穿好衣服 - 不不不
All right. Let me get dressed. - No, no, no, no.
局里有条纹衫在等着你 帅哥
We got some stripes at the station for you, pretty boy.
扯鸡巴蛋
This is bullshit.
我没杀任何人 - 你们不能随便抓人
I didn't kill anyone. - You can't do that.
他和我在一起的 - 娜特 别紧张
He was with me! - Nennete, relax.
他们没有证据 - 没人相信妓女的
They got nothin'. - Nobody believes a whore.
娜特 - 回房间里去
Nennete! - Get back in your room.
我马上就回来
Honestly, I'll be back in no time.
巴比 巴比 - 别担心
Papi! Papi! - Don't worry. Don't worry.
巴比
Papi!
他没杀任何人
He didn't kill anyone!
他当时和我在一起
He was with me!
离铁围栏远点
Step away from the bars!
真不敢相信 他们判你无期徒刑
I can't believe they gave you a life sentence.
你得上诉
You need to appeal.
上诉什么
Appeal what?
娜特 这是诬陷
Nennete, this is a frame-up.
他们全都有份
They're all in on it.
我会集中精力出来的
I just need to concentrate on breaking out.
好
Okay.
我出狱后第一件事 就是要杀了做伪证的人
First thing I'm gonna do when I get back is kill that lying rat witness
还有任何与之有关的人
and anyone who has anything to do with this.
冷静 - 访客时间到
Calm down. - All visitors have to leave!
娜特 你得忘掉我
Nennete, you need to forget about me.
别这么说
Don't say that.
我爱你
I love you.
时间到了 女士 - 巴比 我爱你
Time's up, lady. - Papi, I love you.
快点走吧
Come on. Come on. Come on.
快点离开 - 把你的手拿开
Come on. Come on. Come on! - Get your hands off me!
你是巴比龙吧 你被害惨了
Papillon, right? They fucked you good, huh?
诬陷你谋杀
Framed you for murder.
说你是个窃贼
Say you're one hell of a safecracker.
我更像是砸橱窗抢劫者 我是朱洛特
I'm more of a smash-and-grab guy myself. Name's Julot.
有钱吗
Got any money?
没有吗
No?
必须有点钱 没钱你可跑不了
Get some. You'll never escape without it.
快点进去
Keep goin', keep goin'. Let's keep goin'.
下一个 往前走 - 快点往前走
Next. Move forward. - Next, come on!
走走走起来 - 下一个
Let's go, let's go. - Next.
排好队 - 走到尽头
Line up. - Go to the end.
快往前走
Come on. Move along.
排成一队
Stay in line. - Hey.
也许我可以和你上司谈谈 - 当然
Perhaps I could speak with your supervisor. - Sure.
随便你说
Whatever you say.
路易·德加 他是个百万富翁
Louis Dega. Guy's a millionaire.
因为伪造国防债券 被破获
Busted making counterfeit defense bonds.
不用很久的 - 下一个
Won't last long. - Next.
监狱里每一个犯人 都想破开他肚子拿钱
Every con in the prison will wanna cut him open to get the money he's carrying.
下一个
Next.
从现在起
As of this moment,
你们属于法属圭亚那刑事管理局
you are the property of the Penal Administration of French Guiana.
服刑完毕之后
After serving your full term in prison,
你将留在南美
you will remain in South America
作为工人和殖民者 时间等同于你的刑期
as workers and colonists for a period equal to that of your original sentence.
这是为了法国扩张的利益
This is for the greater good that is French expansion.
至于法国
As for France...
已经和你断绝了关系
she has disowned you.
法国与你们撇清了关系
She has rid herself of you... altogether.
忘了法国吧
Forget France.
现在穿上衣服
Now dress yourselves.
我们要去地狱吗
Are we going to hell?
往上看继续走
Look up. Just keep walking.
德加先生
Mr. Dega.
几周之内 你就能上诉
Your appeal is in a few weeks.
要坚强 路易斯 我爱你
Be strong, Louis. I love you.
我爱你
I love you.
圣诞之前你能到家
You'll be home before Christmas.
德加先生 看这边 德加先生
Dega. Mr. Dega, here. Look this way. Mr. Dega.
69 70
Sixty-nine, 70.
没错 - 动起来
That's right. - Move it!
够了
That's enough.
脚步迅速点
Pick your feet up.
朱洛特
Hey, Julot!
两个两个的
All right, pair up.
去角落里
Hey. - Take the corner.
看来德加已经交了朋友了
Looks like Dega's making friends already.
朱洛特 帮我看着这个吊床
Julot, make sure no one takes this hammock.
我在旁边给你留了地方
I saved you a spot next to me.
有很多人盯着你
You got a lot of eyes on you.
我能保证你的安全
I can keep you safe.
但我需要钱逃跑
All I need's enough money for an escape.
不便宜 但保证你的安全
Won't be cheap, but you'll be safe.
黄鼠狼给鸡拜年吗
Said the scorpion to the frog.
我们都是黄鼠狼 伙计
We're all scorpions in here, pal.
我还不如打点警卫
I think I'd be better off taking my chances setting up in front of the guards.
你同意吗
Wouldn't you agree?
你似乎是那种很有思想的人
You seem like the kind of man who can make up his own mind.
你判断人很准
You're a good judge of character.
祝你晚安
Have a good night.
也祝你晚安
Yeah, you too.
嘿
Hey.
我们组队逃跑吧
Me and you, we should team up for an escape.
如果由于计划不周逃跑被抓 我宁可是自己的错
If I get caught in some half-assed escape, I want it to be my mistake.
全都给我安静
Settle down now!
嘘
Shh.
我知道你把钱藏在肚子里
I know you hide your money in your guts.
顶层甲板
Upper deck.
全都给我回去
Move it back. Back, you.
退后
Back. Back up.
把他带出去
Get him outta here.
这些畜生可以自己清理烂摊子
The animals can clean up their own mess.
去把他扔掉
Come on. Get rid of him.
好戏结束了
Show's over.
昨晚睡得怎么样
How'd you sleep last night?
有自由的味道
Smells like freedom.
你听说过有人越狱吗
What, you've heard of someone escaping the prison?
越了也不一定能成功
Doesn't mean it can't be done.
我感觉希望渺茫
I have trouble seeing hope in hopelessness.
我需要你这样的人
That's why I need a man like you.
我重新考虑了你的提议
I've reconsidered your offer.
保证我活着 直到我们到岛上
Keep me alive until I'm set up on the island,
你任何越狱的费用由我支付
I'll underwrite any escape you care to arrange.
行
All right.
届时你又不会跟我走
And when the time comes, you're not comin' with me.
我并不想逃
I have no intention of escaping.
不像你 我只是想活着
Unlike you, I enjoy being alive.
我老婆在忙我的上诉
My wife's working on my appeal.
我圣诞节之前能到家的
I'm confident I'll be home by Christmas.
乐观主义者
A fellow optimist.
四
Four.
二
Two.
看你干了什么
Look what the fuck you did!
拿刀子
Get the knife!
快 拿刀子
Come on! Get the knife!
拿刀子
Get the knife!
我要杀了你
I'll kill you!
蒸汽 打开蒸汽
Steam! Turn on the steam!
去死
Fuck you!
⚔快点快点
Come on, come on, come on.
退后
Get back!
脱衣 排队 畜生们 否则再次放蒸汽
Strip and line up, you fuckin' animals, or it's the steam again.
快脱衣服
Strip down!
把刀子给我
Gimme the fuckin' knife.
快点 - 全都给我排队
Move it! - Come on. Line up back there!
快点脱衣服
Let's go! Strip down!
快点 - 站起来
Come on, come on. - On your feet.
去后面排队
Line up back there.
把衣服脱掉
Strip down. Strip right up.
手伸出来
Hands. Hands out.
所有人手伸出来
Everybody, hands out. - Everyone, let's have your hands out.
让我们看看
Let's see. What you got?
带他去医务室
Get him to the infirmary.
把你们的肉手拿出来
Let's get this piece of meat outta here.
说让我看 - 手掌翻过来
Show me your hands. Let's see. - Turn 'em over.
你
You.
这家伙肯定有参与打架
This one's been fighting for sure.
带他去头等舱
Take him to first class.
快点走
Come on. Come on!
该走了
Time to go.
头等舱 我们走
First class, let's go.
规矩一点 女士们
Try and behave, ladies.
你应该做掉他的
You should have finished him.
我不想杀人
I don't want to kill anyone.
我要把自己送到医院去
I'm gonna get myself sent to the hospital.
如果有警卫看过来就警告我
Let me know if a guard looks this way.
别停 - 快点
Do not stop! - Get a move on!
嘘
Shh.
快点 你俩
Move it, now! You two!
快点走 - 疯了 朱洛特
Move it! Move it! - Crazy, Julot.
你们走这边 你们两个走那一边
Go that way! You go this way! You two, come on down.
排成一队
Form a line.
我说了排成一队 快点走
Form a line, I said. Form a line. Go ahead.
你俩呆在这儿 呆在队伍里
You two, you stay here. Go back in line.
快走
Move.
快点往那边走
Move it! Come on! That way!
快 快点
Come on! Move it! Come on.
我说了叫你快点 起来
I said move it, goddamn it. Get up. Get up!
来吧 - 往前走 往前走
Come on. - Move along! Move along!
眼睛往前看
Eyes straight. Eyes straight.
快点动起来
Come on. Move it. - Move it!
那条路 - 下梯子
That way. - Down the ladder!
那边 快 再快一点
Over there. Come on. - Faster!
快点 快点
Move it. Move it!
动起来
Come on now. - Come on. Move.
不要盯着我
Don't be looking at me like that.
快点 - 你也是
Come on. Move. - You too.
往前
Move along.
伙计们 把他弄起来
Guys, get him up!
我的腿
My fucking leg!
我的腿 我的腿
My leg. My leg!
够了 够了
That's enough. That's enough.
全都分开
Break it up. Break it up. That's enough.
全都给我回队伍去
Move it! - Move. Back to the line.
闪开
Move, move.
喊到名字的就举手
Raise your hand if I call your name.
奥古斯丁
Augustin.
巴尔巴 - 来吧 呆在队伍里
Barba. - Come on now. Stay in line.
贝莱尔
Bellaire.
往前走 那边
Move along! Over there.
洛夫顿
Lofton.
纳瓦兰
Navarrone.
出发
Move out!
好了快点
All right, come on. Move it.
继续走
Keep moving!
犯人 停步
Prisoners, halt!
打开大门
Open the gates.
前进
March.
我知道你们许多人想逃跑
I know many of you at this very moment are thinking about escape.
有胆子就来试试
Feel free to try whenever you like.
我们很乐于向你们开枪
We'll be happy to shoot you.
但如果你们想避免这种下场
If, however, you should avoid that mercy,
总有两个哨兵在执勤...
there are two guardians who are always on duty...
在丛林里只能挨饿
The bush, where the best thing that can happen to you is starvation.
你也可以选择跳海
Or you could choose the sea,
我保证 鲨鱼也总是很饿
where sharks too, I assure you, are always hungry.
第一次逃跑未果
If you manage to survive your first attempt,
单独囚禁两年
you'll get two years in solitary.
第二次逃跑未果 单独囚禁五年
Second attempt, five years in solitary,
第三次就是恶魔岛的无期徒刑
followed by a life sentence at Devil's Island.
如果你杀了人
If you commit murder...
你会被处决的
you'll be executed.
就这样
That's all.
让开
Move. Move.
上帝啊
Jesus Christ.
去角落
Take the corner.
睁大眼睛 别动
Hey, keep your eyes open and don't move.
谁决定分配工作的
Who decides what work we get assigned to?
原谅我的无礼 - 我不是叫你别动吗
Excuse my ill-mannered... - I thought I told you not to move.
他还不够顺从
He has yet to be tamed.
显然您是个大忙人
And you're obviously a very important, very, very busy man.
我只是狱吏
I'm just the turnkey.
我们要找一个人 保证我们被分配到
We're looking for someone to ensure we're assigned
早晨的工作
the right sort of work in the morning.
这要一千块钱
It'll cost you a thousand.
我不这么认为
I don't think so.
这显然是狮子大开口
No, now that seems entirely too high.
先生 看来我们搞错了
Sir, I think we started off on the wrong foot.
一千块其实很公平
I think a thousand is actually fair.
现在工作有没有得选...
Now, is there a selection of work you have...
比如去医院
Attendants at the hospital.
一千块足够买一袋烟草
And for a thousand, you can throw in a pouch of tobacco.
还有笔记本 - 笔记本?
And a notebook. - A notebook?
我是艺术家 - 你是伪造犯
I'm an artist. - You're a forger.
你是个窃贼 我对这个职业无感
And you're a safecracker, a profession of which I thoroughly disapprove.
但我是个诚实的罪犯
At least I'm an honest criminal. - Hmm.
现在就得给钱
Hey. I'm gonna need that right now.
我是说现在
I mean, right now.
抱歉
Excuse me.
我想你得去洗手间了
I think you need to go to the bathroom.
当然
Yes, of course.
恕我失陪 先生们
If you'll excuse me, gentlemen.
你要去哪
Where you goin'?
我又没来过这里
I've never been here before.
马桶在那儿 公主
Toilet's there, princess.
什么样的人会把谋生之物藏在屁股里
What animal but a man keeps his only means of survival up his ass?
有东西咬我
Something bit me.
有人跑了
We got a runner!
锁门
Lockdown! - Lock it down!
哪个营 - 不 是从医院跑的
Which barracks? - No, he broke out the hospital.
就一个人 - 医院吗
Just one. - The hospital?
把你们这营门锁起来
Lock down your barrack.
我肯定是朱洛特 - 锁门
I'll bet that's Julot. - Lock it down!
这家伙急得不可救药
Son of a bitch didn't waste any time.
你看
You see?
这是可以做到的
It can be done.
锁起来 进入丛林 退后
Lock it down! Into the jungle. Stand down.
路线零
Route Zero.
我朋友和我必须在一起
My friend and I need to be kept together at all times.
这两个去医院
Set these two up in the hospital.
可能需要几天的时间在我恢复...
And it'll be a few days before I'm well enough to do any sort of...
算了
Don't push it.
他们两个 路线零
Both of them, Route Zero.
德加先生 停一下
Mr. Dega, stop.
我认识你 你认识我吗
I know you. Do you know me?
当然 先生
Yes. Yes, of course, sir.
副典狱长先生
You're the deputy warden, sir.
我姐姐的丈夫被逮捕了
My sister's husband was arrested
因为出售你在马赛给他提供的假国防债券
selling counterfeit defense bonds you furnished him with in Marseilles.
德加在马赛是个常用名
Dega is a very common name in Marseilles.
桑蒂尼 - 在 长官
Santini. - Yes, sir.
他直接去路线零
This one goes straight to Route Zero.
把他带走
Take him away.
等等
Wait.
他也一起
Take him too.
我们这里尽量不分开老朋友
We try not to separate old friends here.
让他们去路线零 去
Get them to Route Zero. Move.
什么是路线零
What is Route Zero?
注意
Stand clear!
再一轮
Your other round!
我感觉不太好
I don't feel so good.
看着点
Watch it now!
去放到车里
It go... It goes in the cart.
往前走
Move along.
你话说太多了
You do a lot of talking.
我有吗 - 是 别再说了
I do? - Yeah. Stop that.
有助于打发时间
It passes... It passes the time.
别让我看见你 - 去拿大石头
Get outta my face. Get outta my face. - You take the bigger rock.
你要是和他打 我可护不了你
You get into a fight with him, I'm not protecting you.
如果你老婆在这里
If your wife was here...
而你在巴黎 拥有所有的钱
you were in Paris with all that money,
你愿意付多少钱让她出来
how much would you pay to get her back?
我所有的钱
Everything I have.
那么她会为你付多少
How much would she pay for you?
你是个真乐观主义者
You're a real optimist.
小个子 你得用点力
Little man. Little man. You need to put some weight in.
你得用力推
You can push harder than that. Come on.
相信我他不行
Trust me, he can't.
相信我他必须这么做
Trust me, he has to.
快推
Come on! Push it!
推 - 加快步伐
Push it! - Pick up the pace.
我 我腹泻
I have... I have diarrhea.
你想我怎么办
What you want me to do about it?
不 你不明白
No, you don't understand.
我把钱丢了
I lost the money.
为什么不动了
What's the holdup?
你在干什么
What the hell are you doing?
什么 - 少搞事
What? - Stop shitting around.
你会害死我们的 - 管好你自己的车
You'll get us all killed. - You mind your own cart.
这个小个子会害我们干更多的活
The little guy is making more work for the rest of us.
管好你自己的事 - 全都散开
Mind your own business. - Break it up. Break it up.
你在做什么 起来
What are you doing? Get up.
起来 起来
Get up! Get up.
站起来 - 我不能
On your feet. - I can't.
把他抬起来
Pick him up.
把他抬起来 放进车里
Come on, pick him up. Put him in the cart.
回去工作
Back to work.
推车吧
Move your carts.
你只干一份工 却也干不好
You had one job to do. You couldn't do it.
我的身体在反抗
My body's in revolt.
钱在哪里
Where is it now?
你觉得呢
Where do you think?
我信任谁也比信小偷好
I should have known better than to trust a thief.
我用不着偷走已经属于我的东西
I can't steal what's already mine.
回营房之后就给你
As soon as we get back to the barracks, you're taking it back.
这次你要拿稳了
And you're gonna hold onto it this time.
把你屁股缝起来也行
I don't care if you have to sew your ass up to do it.
对不起
I'm sorry.
因为我用怀疑的眼光误判了你
I may have prematurely judged you with an unworthy degree of suspicion.
你就少得瑟了
Well, don't propose yet.
我只是不喜欢屁股缝里夹着东西
I just don't like carrying things in my ass.
他死了
He's dead.
他死了 - 闭嘴 小鸟
He's dead! - Shut up, birdie.
你是笨蛋怎么的
Are you stupid or what?
我们分享他的口粮 给
We share his ration. Here.
给
Here.
你给自己找了个男朋友吧
So you got yourself a boyfriend, huh?
你是海军吗
You were in the navy?
你以为呢
What do you think?
可能是"囚犯"
I thought maybe it meant "jailbird."
燕子 它代表着希望
Swallows. It stands for hope.
到达陆地时看到的第一样活物
First thing you see when you reach land.
我知道 - 是吗 怎么会
I know. - Yeah? How come?
你是海军吗
You were in the navy?
十八个月
Eighteen months.
双桅船 六个人 不合适我
Followed by six in the brig. Didn't suit me.
一只蝴蝶
A butterfly.
你现在是小偷了
So you're a thief now?
我猜那也不适合你
Guess that didn't suit you either.
我们该改天去航海
We should go sailing sometime.
你有船吗
You got a boat?
你有钱吗
Can you get any of that?
也许
Maybe.
那么 到时候告诉我
Well, let me know then.
你男朋友有麻烦了
Your boyfriend's got trouble.
给我你的钱 不然你和你朋友全都去死
Give me your money, or you and your friend will die.
有麻烦吗 - 我在和你婊子说话
Is there trouble? - I was talking to your bitch.
现在你在跟我说话
Now you're talking to me.
现在回牢房
Work it out in the barracks!
休息结束
Break is over.
快排队
Get in line!
休息结束 前进
Break is over. Forward march.
排队
Line it up. Line it up!
停 停
Stop. Stop!
转身 眼睛看前面
Turn around. Eyes up front. Come on.
你知道暴风雨过后 让女士们经过会是什么结果的
You know better than to truck your ladies through here after a rainstorm.
是啊 你能帮我吗
Yeah. Can you help me out?
我会帮你的
I'll make it good for you.
⚔把姑娘们带上来
Get the girls up here.
快
Come on.
小心
Watch out.
Watch out...
你能听见我吗
Can you hear me?
带我去海边要多少钱
How much to take me up the coast?
别傻了
Don't be stupid.
我给你2000
I'll give you 2,000.
警卫
Guard!
看在上帝的份上 不要举报我
Don't turn me in, for Christ's sake.
4,000.
有什么问题
What's the problem?
我在考虑把哪个姑娘给你 算作回报
Just wanted to know which girl I should send to repay you.
没主的就行
One that hasn't caught anything yet.
我的船在河的另一边
My boat is on the other side of the river.
我在那里会呆三天
I'll be there for three more days.
现在是5000
It's 5,000.
该死的小偷
You're a goddamned thief.
澳门新葡京娱乐城 www.941.net 日本AV女优现场发牌，注册即送15元，可提款，
百家乐日送88万，100万提款3分钟火速到账，网址是：www.941.net 官方直营，大额无忧
警卫来了 - 别碰我
The guards are coming. - Don't fucking touch me!
我不知道会这样
I didn't know it would be like this.
我可能还没等到上诉就死了
I'll be dead long before my appeal.
我要和你一起走
I need to go with you.
当初可没这么说
That wasn't part of the deal.
是 我知道 但我还是要和你一起走
Yes, I realize that, but I still have to go with you.
你坐过船吗
You ever sail a boat?
有没有出过海
Spend any time at sea?
有 我在海上呆过很多天
Yes, I have spent a number of days at sea.
我和很多人被关在笼子里
I was locked in a cage for most of them.
所以我很理解这个概念
But I think I understand the concept well enough.
你不能跟我走 德加
You can't come with me, Dega.
你该叫我路易斯
You should call me Louis.
继续
Keep it moving.
让他们排队
Get 'em in line.
站直了
Stand straight!
跪下
Down on your knees.
脱掉帽子 交叉双臂
Take off your hats and cross your arms.
在行刑的那一刻 你们都要低头
At the moment of execution, you're all to bow your heads.
有人刺伤了两名警卫
A man stabbed two guards...
其中一个今早死亡
one of whom died this morning,
两个孩子失去了父亲
leaving two children without their father.
为了什么
And for what?
以便他越过丛林
So he could go on a run through the jungle.
感谢诸位到来
Thank you for coming!
看我下地狱吧
Watch me go to hell!
犯人就位
Prisoner ready.
留着你没有好处 毁掉你也没有损失
Keeping you is no benefit. Destroying you is no loss.
你
You.
选个犯人
Pick another inmate.
去抬尸体
You carry the body.
去把船准备好
Go get the boat ready.
他死了
He's gone.
这些只是血肉
It's just flesh and blood.
为什么停下来
Why are you stopping?
你在做什么
What are you doing?
快走
Move.
我说 你到底在干什么
I said, what the hell are you doing?
起来
Get up.
起来 你这个小虫子
You get up, you little worm.
给我站起来
Get your ass up.
你这个小虫子
You little worm.
该死
Oh, shit.
站住
Stop! Hey, stop!
有人跑了
We've got a runner!
他朝北走了
He's heading north.
巴比
Papi.
巴比 - 往北走
Papi? - Heading north now!
巴比龙
Papillon!
注意林际线
Check the tree line.
把他抬起来
Pick him up.
快 快
Come on. Come on.
你真是个好人
Oh. You're a good man.
我当然是个好人 想要他的钱
Yeah, I'm a good man that wants his money.
我没有带钱
Look, I don't have it.
没在我身上
Not with me.
但我会给你的
But I'm gonna make it worth your while.
我在巴黎很有钱
I got a lot of money in Paris.
我会把所有的都给你
I'll give you everything I got.
即使你有钱
Even if you had the money...
典狱长会付给我们双倍的钱
the warden will pay us double.
王八蛋
Son of a bitch.
你很幸运 警卫没死
You're lucky that guard didn't die.
否则你会上断头台的
Otherwise, you would have met the guillotine.
现在你将被转移到圣约瑟夫岛
Now you'll be transferred to the island of Saint Joseph,
在那里单独关两年
where you'll serve a two-year sentence in solitary confinement.
没有医疗
There's no rehabilitation.
因为毫无用处
We know that's useless,
我们会尽力让你崩溃的
so we do our best to break you.
那里经常有怪事
Strange things happen there.
尤其是那些抱着希望的人
Especially to those who cling to hope,
因为在圣约瑟夫岛 没有希望
because there is no hope on Saint Joseph.
只有沉默
Just silence.
你听到典狱长说的了
You heard the warden.
时刻保持沉默
Silence must be observed at all times.
还以为你插了翅膀
Thought you grew wings, didn't you?
抓住他
Grab him.
我教教你什么是安静
I'll teach you to be quiet.
你再敢偷窥
You make another peep...
你就别想再活了
you might not survive your time here.
他疯了 我们走吧
Come on. He's crazy. Come on. Come on.
好好享受你的两年
Enjoy your next two years here.
⚔你的桶里每天会有一枚椰子 从现在起
德加
Dega.
等等 需要检查
Hold on. Need to check that.
那是什么
What is that, hmm?
谁付钱让你带进来的 王八蛋
Somebody paying you to bring this shit in here? Son of a bitch.
谁付钱给你的
Huh? Who's paying you?
谁付你钱 你个孙子
Who's paying you, you son of a bitch?
不
No!
天那 你是不是杀了他
Jesus! I think you killed him.
把尸体弄出去 收拾干净
Get that body out of here and clean up the mess.
你到底在想什么
What the hell were you thinking?
难怪你还没有崩溃
No wonder you haven't broken yet.
有多久了
How long has it being going on?
你可以说话
You may speak.
送椰子的是谁
Who sent you those coconuts?
如果不坦白
If you don't fess up...
口粮减一半
I'll put you on half rations.
交出那个人就饶你一命
You're choosing another man's life over your own.
口粮减一半
Put him on half rations.
我给你带了点汤来
I brought you some soup.
里面有肉
It's got meat in it.
说出他的名字
Just tell me his name.
Tell me his name.
人发疯的时候 自己会知道吗
You think a person knows when he's going mad?
或者你认为这反而是一种盲目乐观
Or you think it's blissful ignorance?
因为答案要靠你自己找
'Cause you're about to find out.
剩下的刑期让他在黑暗中过
Put him in darkness for the remainder of his sentence.
也可能刑期未满 就死了
Or the remainder of his life,
以先到者为准
whichever comes first.
Six.
Two.
Twenty-four.
6-2-24
6-2-24.
Twenty-four.
逃的不错
This is a good escape.
他还活着吗
Is he still alive?
两年了
Two years are up.
我知道有些人 在这一刻
I know that some of you, at this very moment,
正在计划逃跑
are thinking about escape.
有胆子就来试试
Feel free to try whenever you like.
我们很乐于向你们开枪
We'll be happy to shoot you.
但如果你们想避免这种下场
However, should you avoid that mercy,
总有两个哨兵在执勤...
there are two guardians who are always on duty.
在丛林里只能挨饿
The bush, where the best thing that can happen to you is starvation.
你也可以选择跳海
Or you could choose the sea,
那里的鲨鱼也总是很饿
where the sharks too, are always hungry.
第一次逃跑未果
If you manage to survive your first attempt,
单独囚禁两年
you'll get two years in solitary.
第二次逃跑未果 单独囚禁五年
Second attempt is five years in solitary,
第三次就是恶魔岛的无期徒刑
followed by a life sentence at Devil's Island.
如果你杀了人
If you commit murder...
你会被处决的
...you'll be executed.
就这样
That's all.
巴比
Papi.
我想早点来的
I wanted to come sooner,
但我担心你不想见我
but I was afraid you wouldn't wanna see me.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你在这里 全是我的错
It's my fault you're here.
正如你预测的
As you predicted, um,
我的上诉遭到了麻烦
my appeal's run into some problems.
但我老婆处理得当
But my wife's doing very well.
她最近嫁给了我的律师
She recently married my lawyer.
那么 和她一起下地狱吧
Well, to hell with her then.
你这狗娘养的
You son of a bitch.
我还以为你傻了
I thought you'd gone simple on me.
你这么想就对了
That's the idea.
你知道交出我的名字
You know you'd have had a much easier time
你会活得更轻松
if you'd just given them my name.
我考都没有考虑过
It's not like I didn't think about it.
我知道你很脆弱
I just know how goddamn delicate you are.
嗯
Mm.
恐怕换成我
I fear under similar circumstances
我早就交代了
I would've fared differently.
不知道你是怎么做到的
I don't know how you made it.
我习惯了沉默
I just got used to the silence.
如果我能出去
If I ever get out...
我要过一种不同的生活
I'm gonna live a different kind of life.
这个星期日 典狱长将在院子里放电影
This Sunday, the warden will be showing a film in the courtyard,
招待当地政客
entertaining some local politicians.
会很吵的
It'll be loud.
警卫要值两班 岗哨间隔非常远
The guards will be doing double-duty, spread very thin.
这是你最好的机会
This is your best chance.
你能搞到船吗
Can you get a boat?
不
No.
赛利亚呢 他还在吗
What about Celier? Is he still here?
很不幸 他还在
Unfortunately, yes.
只要他还有船
If he can still get a boat...
你的钱够付吗
do you have enough money to pay for it?
可能 他可能会和我们一起走
Well, I might, but then he'd wanna come with us.
我们
Us?
Us.
行
All right.
但我们还是需要一条船
But we still need a boat.
你现在就走
You leave now!
走
Leave!
出去
Get out!
Get out! Leave!
出去
Get out!
这个人疯了 - 离开
This man's mad! - Go!
出去 - 他疯了
Get out! - He's out of his mind!
不不不
No! No, no, no, no!
不
No!
不 - 他疯了
No! - He's out of his mind!
帮帮我
Help me! Help me!
来吧 巴比
Come, Papi. Here.
冷静 冷静点 放开他
Come on, come... Calm down, calm down. Let him go.
放开他
Let him go!
没事的
It's okay, it's okay.
嘘嘘
Shh, shh.
给我拿点药片来
Bring me some pills.
吃一颗药吧
Come on. Take one.
给我拿点水来
Bring me some water.
吞下去
Swallow.
没事的
It'll be okay.
熄灯 十分钟后
Lights out, ten minutes.
嘘嘘
Shh, shh.
你离我远点 - 放松
Get off of me. - Just relax!
放开我 - 放松
Leave me! - Relax.
滚 别想干我
Get off! I will never let you fuck me.
嘘嘘
Shh, shh.
你很快会知道下场的
You will soon, if you know what's good for you.
嘿
Hey.
我只想谈谈
Hey, I just wanna talk.
我不是妓女 - 我没想那样
I'm not a goddamn whore. - That's not what I want.
每个人都这么说
Yeah, everybody says that until they do.
相信我 我没那个想法
Trust me, I don't.
我有提议
I got a different proposition.
如果你碎碎念 对你没好处
If you repeat one word of this, it's not gonna be good for you.
我不想知道 - 也许你想
I don't wanna know then. - Maybe you do.
我简单说一下
Look, I'm puttin' something together.
这个星期天
This Sunday.
我们还有一个空缺
We got room for one more.
⚔我没有东西给你
I have nothing to offer you.
我要你去分散狱吏的注意力
I need you to distract that turnkey.
让他到时候进来 拖住他
Get him to come in here at a certain time, keep him occupied.
如果我做了
If I do that,
你最好计划周详
your plan better work.
会奏效的
It'll work.
可没那么容易
It's not gonna be easy.
你一个人能做到吗
Can you handle yourself?
你是被陷害谋杀的吧
You were framed for murder, right?
没人敢陷害我
Well, nobody framed me.
那是赛利亚
That's Celier.
他给我们搞了条船
He's gotten us a boat.
手伸出来
Let's see the arm.
感染
Infected.
干得好
Good job.
巴比
Papi!
你这个瘦猴子
You skinny son of a bitch.
很高兴见到你
Good to see you.
你把手怎么了
What'd you do to your arm?
我自己割伤的
I had to cut myself to get in here.
这招还有用吗 - 没什么的 别想了
It still work? - Yeah, it's nothing. Don't think about it.
我还能揍死你 - 我快点吗 我得回去了
I can still kick your ass. - Can we hurry this up? I have to get back.
小鸟 你能闭嘴吗
Birdie, can you shut up for once?
这是马屈瑞 我们的第四个人
This is Maturette. He's our fourth.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
一个人行吗 - 行 用刀子
You know how to handle yourself? - Yeah, with a knife.
好吧 放松点 - 活泼的小个子
All right, take it easy. - Feisty little one, huh?
你们都准备好了吗 - 是 我准备好了
You all set? - Yeah, I'm set.
我有人在岸边藏了一条船
I got a guy that's hiding a boat on the bank.
在河的上游
It's upriver a ways.
从那里可以直接进入大海
From there, it's a straight shot to the ocean.
现在要交一半的钱
But we need half the money now.
你呢
What about you?
电影一开始 我们就穿过典狱长的大楼
When the film starts, we'll go through the warden's building.
我会有钥匙的
I'll have a key.
那就定了
We got a plan.
定了
你没事吧
You all right?
没事
No.
我们能信任他吗
I'm not sure we can trust him.
这家伙难以预测
Look at him, he's unpredictable.
他就像笼中兽
He's like a caged animal.
我们都是笼中兽 伙计
We're all animals in here, pal.
他会没事的
He'll be fine.
他现在需要钱
He needs the money now.
给
Here.
是他们给我的镇静剂
It's the sedatives they gave me.
放进警卫的咖啡里
Get 'em in the guards' coffee.
其他的交给我们
We'll do the rest.
我得回去了
I have to get back.
你干得不错
You're doin' good.
看看这是什么
Hey. - What do we have here, huh?
去死吧
Go to hell.
还给我
Give me those back.
他会搞砸我们的计划的
He's gonna fuck up our plan.
没事的
It's gonna be fine.
你他妈在干什么 伙计
What the fuck are you doing, man?
够了
All right! That's enough!
都给我分开
Break it up! Break it up!
偶尔我也会出上一拳
I had to figure I'd know how to throw a punch
因为我父亲经常打我
considering how often my father used to beat me.
你的也是吗
Yours too?
我父母是老师
My parents are school teachers.
今晚见
See ya tonight.
典狱长要茴香酒
Anisette for the warden.
拿出你最好的
The best you have.
给我一瓶
Just give me the bottle.
金刚
有两三个
Here's two or three.
先生们 想醒一醒咖啡吗
Would you gentlemen like your coffees freshened?
拿过来
Bring it on in.
典狱长请客
Compliments of the warden.
很好
Very nice.
拿着
Here.
杀了人就得上断头台
If we kill someone and this goes wrong, it's the guillotine.
所以不要杀人
No one dies.
再给我来一杯
Give me another one of them.
行
All right.
德加
Dega!
你要去哪里
Where are you going?
德加
Dega!
典狱长 现在
The warden. Now!
别动 嘘 嘘
Stop! Shh, shh!
嘘 嘘
Shh, shh!
什么声音
What was that?
我最好去看看
I'd better go check.
果然有用
It's working.
老兄
Oh, man.
我们来太早了
We're too early.
有打火机吗
Hey, got a light?
当然有 先生
Yes, of course, sir.
大家进去吧
Oh! Oh! Okay, go inside.
所有人都进去吧
Everybody, go inside. Come on.
来吧 亲爱的 - 操
Come on, darling. - Fuck.
我们从这里走 - 不 不
That's our way out. - No, no.
他在干什么
What's he doin'?
停电了 - 操
Power's off! - Fuck!
巴比 我们得走了 不能待在这里
Papi, we gotta move. We can't stay here.
我们等德加
We wait for Dega.
忘掉德加吧
Forget about Dega!
他不可靠
He's not reliable.
你知道的
And you know it!
我们走吧 快
Let's just go. Come on.
你要走吗
You wanna go?
那就走
Go.
你跟我一起吗
You with me?
打开大门
Uh, yeah. Open the gate.
你怎么了
What's wrong with you?
我偷到了钥匙 可以去中央走道
Ha! I stole the keys to get us up to the central walkway.
通向哨塔
We can take that to the guard tower.
只要灯不亮 他们就看不到我们
As long as the lights stay off, they won't see us.
然后跳下去吗
And then we jump?
你有更好的主意吗
You got a better idea?
快
Come on.
Come on!
快
Go, go!
守住围墙
Guard the wall!
你 带我去南墙
You! Take me to the south wall.
是 先生
Yes, sir!
该死
Oh, shit.
好 我们走
All right. Come on. Let's go.
慢一点
Easy.
你没事吧
You all right?
我们走吧 快
Let's go! Come on!
快走快走
Go, go, go.
快
Come on!
跳
Jump!
快
Come on!
快 快
Come on! Come on!
他们会看到你的 快
They're gonna see you! Come on!
快
Come on!
跳 快点
Jump! Come on!
跳
Jump!
妈的
Shit!
腿断了
Hey. It's broken.
别管他了 - 钱在他那里
Leave him. - He's got the money.
马屈瑞 帮我
Maturette, help me.
天那
Christ!
好了来吧
All right, come on.
我们走
Let's go.
快
Come on.
船还有多远
How much further to the boat?
你在拖累我们 德加
You're slowing us down, Dega.
快 必须迅速
Come on. We've got to move faster.
再敢走一步
Don't take another step.
别把我带回去
You're not takin' me back.
那得看你带没带钱
That depends if you have my money.
巴比 没事的
Papi. It's okay.
这是我的船上的人
This is my guy with the boat.
船在哪
Where's our boat?
在河的上游
It's a ways up the river.
想要去那里 先给钱
Want me to take you there, pay me.
不然就弄死你
Or fuck you.
我就这点钱了
This is all I have left.
不要告诉别人
Let's keep that between us.
享受自由吧
Enjoy your freedom!
这什么破船
Fuck! What kind of shit boat did you get us?
闭嘴 德加
Shut up, Dega!
你能上船就够走运了 继续舀水
You're lucky to be here. Keep bailing!
把水弄出去
Get it outta the boat.
我在努力
I'm trying.
别泼在我身上 德加 该死的
Don't throw it at me, Dega. Goddamn it.
泼到海里去 - 我是泼到海里的
Throw it in the water! - I'm throwing it at the water.
马屈瑞 - 在
Maturette! - Yes?
检查舵柄
Check the tiller.
我来了
I got it, I got it.
巴比
Papi.
这艘船坐不下所有人
This boat can't hold all of us. You know it.
我们要减轻重量
We need to lighten the weight.
反正他会死的 巴比
He's gonna die anyway, Papi.
没人死
Nobody needs to die.
操 掉了
Fuck! It fell off!
去修理舵柄 - 坏了啊
Fix the tiller! - It's broken.
修舵
Fix the tiller!
闪开
Move!
拜托
Come on.
你拿一下
Here, take this. Take this.
马屈瑞 帮我
Maturette, help me.
暴风雨 船会沉的
This storm is gonna sink the boat.
必须立即采取行动
We need to act, and we need to act now.
我要把船备好
Just let me get the boat ready.
你是不是疯了
Did you lose your mind? Huh?
你想因为这个家伙而死吗
You wanna die because of this guy?
没有人会死
Nobody needs to die.
我不可能都活着
Well, we can't all live.
德加 他是死沉死沉的
Dega, he's dead weight.
你有多少钱
How much money you have?
他没有钱
He doesn't have any money.
他没有钱吗
He doesn't have any money?
你听到了吗 马屈瑞
You hear that, Maturette?
他们一直在骗我们
They've been lying to us.
你想为他而死吗
You wanna die for him?
现在是二对一 巴比
That makes it two against one, Papi.
让开
Step aside.
你什么都不需要做
You don't need to do anything.
让开 巴比
Step aside, Papi!
我不会为那家伙死的
I'm not gonna die for that guy.
最后一次机会 巴比让开
Last chance, Papi. Step aside!
我不了解你 但我要回家了
I don't know about you, I'm going home!
住手
Stop!
够了
Enough! That's enough!
That's enough.
够了
Enough.
⚔欢迎
Welcome.
我还有另外两个人
I was traveling with two other men.
他们都在
They are being cared for.
我们在哪
Where are we?
这里是哥伦比亚
This is Colombia.
我们知道你来自哪里
We know where you've come from.
你只需忏悔
But you need only repent.
上帝会重回你的生活
Allow God back into your life...
你会被宽恕的
and you'll be forgiven.
去洗一洗吧
You should go and wash yourself.
然后和我们一起祈祷
Then come and pray with us.
我们还得跑
We need to keep movin'.
他们知道我们从哪来的
They know where we came from.
协议履行完成了
Our deal is done.
我说了不能相信他
I told you we couldn't trust him.
我要走了
I'm leaving.
有没有你都要走
With or without you.
祝好运
Good luck.
巴比 我们成功了
Papi! We made it!
巴比
Papi.
这里是天堂
It's paradise here.
是 但这里不是家
Yeah, but it's not home.
反正不是我的
Not for me, anyway.
祝好运 马屈瑞
Good luck, Maturette.
赶快走
We're leaving.
现在
Now.
快
Come on.
啊 巴比
Aah! - Papi!
马屈瑞
Maturette!
忏悔
Repent.
如果你们真的忏悔
If you are truly sorry for what you have done,
那就没什么可怕的
then you have nothing to fear.
上帝会照顾你的
God will watch over you.
你又回来了
You came back.
来吧巴比
Come on, Papi.
我得亲自来看看
I had to come and see this for myself.
单独关押五年 很少人能活下来
Few men survive five years in solitary.
你活着是为了什么
What were you living for?
因为你绝不会料到你会去...
'Cause I don't think you're gonna find it where you're going...
恶魔岛
Devil's Island.
现在 为人师表的儿子怎么会在这种地方
Now, what's the son of two school teachers doing in a place like this?
那么
Well?
你觉得怎么样
What do you think?
我用了五年的时间画的
I've had five years to work on it.
典狱长对我的反抗不满意
The warden wasn't very happy with my disobedience.
所以他把我直送恶魔岛
So he sent me straight here to Devil's Island.
来吃点东西吧
Let's get some food in you.
太阳照屁股了
Rise and shine.
来吧
Come on.
有活儿要干
There's work to be done.
我们能去海边吗
Can we get to the ocean?
我知道你在想什么
I know what you're thinking.
就算你掉下去没死
But even if you survive the fall...
在海里你也活不了
you'll never survive the ocean.
都是海浪
It's all about the waves.
什么
What?
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
你以为我在说什么
What do you think I'm talkin' about?
回去睡觉吧
Oh, go back to bed.
那是自杀不是逃跑
That's suicide, not escape.
不 听我说
No. Listen.
我们造一艘筏子 下到海里去
All we need to do is build a raft and get it to the ocean.
洋流会把我们带到大陆
The tide will take us straight to the mainland.
过来看看
Just come and see.
来看看
Come and see!
看到吗
See?
顺着洋流而漂
We ride the current to freedom.
我好担心你能不能保护我
I'm a little concerned about your ability to protect me right now.
别担心 跳下去说不定就死了
Don't worry. The fall will probably kill us.
绑在一起吧
Let's tie these together.
我要留下来
I need to stay.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我要留下来
I need to stay.
出于同样的原因 你必须离开
For the same reason you have to go.
我属于这里
I belong here.
没事的
It's okay.
真的
It's good.
快走吧 别浪费时间了
Go on now. You don't wanna waste any more time.
⚔路易斯
Louis!
路易斯
我做到了 你这个伪造犯
I made it, you dirty little forger!
谢谢
Thank you.
1969年
先生
Sir?
您的水
Your water.
谢谢 - 不客气
Thank you. - You're welcome.
我很惊讶你冒险回来
I'm surprised you risked coming back.
我读了诉讼时效
I'd read the statute of limitations.
你仍然是个通缉犯
You're still a wanted man.
我不会待很久的
I won't be here long.
我的家 现在是委内瑞拉了
My home is Venezuela now.
但重要的是
But it's important
我的回忆录 得在这里发表
that my memoir be published here...
在法国
in France.
我老婆说服我写下了一切
My wife convinced me to write it all down...
趁我年轻还记得住
while I'm still young enough to remember.
这真的是你的故事吗
So is this really your story?
这是很多人的故事
It's the story of a lot of men.
8万多名犯人被关在法属圭亚那
绝大多数人再也没有回到法国
亨利·夏里埃尔的自传《巴比龙》 当时占据了法国21周的头号榜单
到目前为止 已售出超过1300万本 有30种语言
1970年 法国司法部长签署了法令 允许夏里埃尔返回法国
他的余生中 作为自由人而活着 法属圭亚那的殖民监狱没有他活得长
⚔⚔⚔字幕组